# GustavoPenha

guzpenha10@gmail.com

#### about

29 years Delft, NL

#### links

webpage twitter github google scholar linkedin

#### languages

portuguese english

#### research

I am a research scientist at Spotify working with search and recommendation. My interests in information retrieval are representation learning, explainability & model understanding.

## **experience**

2023-1-now	Research Scientist Research on search and recommendation problems.	Spotify - NL
2022-6–8	Research Intern Research on query gen. for improving the retrievability of entities (	Spotify - NL CIKM'23).
2021-5–8	<b>Applied Research Intern</b> Research on explanations for Alexa, published 2 papers (CHI'22 & C	mazon - US CHIIR'22).
2015–2018	<b>Data Scientist</b> <i>Machine learning and data science projects. Tech lead of 1M+ R\$</i>	kima - Brazil <i>project.</i>

## selected publications

2023	Improving Content Retrievability in Search with Controllable Query Generation  CIKM  Gustavo Penha, Enrico P, Maryam A, Alice W, Hugues B
2022	Pairwise Review-Based Explanations for Voice Product Search  Gustavo Penha, Eyal Krikon, Vanessa Murdock
2022	Evaluating the Robustness of Retrieval Pipelines with Query Variation Generators Best paper award @ECIR Gustavo Penha, Arthur Câmara, Claudia Hauff
2021	On the Calibration and Uncertainty of Neural L2R Models for Conv.  Search  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff
2020	What does BERT know about books, movies and music? Probing BERT for Conversational Recommendation  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff  RecSys
2020	Curriculum Learning Strategies for IR  Gustavo Penha, Claudia Hauff

### education

2018-2022	Ph.D. TU Delft	- NL	
	Computer Science. 10 papers, 100+ citations and 150+ github stars.		
2012-2018	B.Sc. and M.Sc. UFMG - B	3razil	
	Computer Science. MSc paper won best paper RU award at RecSys'20.	e. MSc paper won best paper RU award at RecSys'20.	